OK,so,what we're gonna do today
我们今天的课
is finish up with the beliefs of self-fulfilling prophecy lecture
要把自我实现预言的信念讲完
and move on to the lecture on focus
并开始讲下一课 关于专注
and how focus creates reality.
和专注如何创造现实
Where did we end last time?
我们上一课讲到哪里?
We ended by talking about Rena and other things.
我们讲到Rena和其他的一些事
We talked about the model,the Dan Gilbert model,
我们讲到模型 Dan Gilbert的模型
the Philip Brickman model,
Philip Brickman模型
where after a failure or a success there is a spike up,
成功或失败过后 会有大起大落
spike down,but then we recover.
但我们会恢复过来
And we basically move along a base level of well being
我们一生基本沿基准的幸福发展
through out our lives,with the ups and downs,the vicissitudes.
其中有起伏和变迁
The question then became,
所以问题是
or rather there was good news and bad news.
或说有好消息也有坏消息
The good news was,we don't really need to worry that much,
好消息是 我们不必太过担心
we can take more risks,we can put ourselves on the line more.
我们能冒更多风险 也更容易回到基准线上
Failure usually,not all failures,
失败往往 虽然不是所有的失败
but usually is just a temporary decline in our wellbeing level,
往往只是使幸福水平暂时的下降
self esteem level,and then every quickly we jump up again.
还有自尊水平 然后会迅速回升
So that's the good news.
所以这是好消息
The bad news is: if we're just around the same base level,
坏消息是 如果我们总是回到原来的水平
you know,why should we put any effort into our wellbeing?
那我们为什么要努力寻求幸福呢?
And the answer to that,
而答案
and the whole course essentially is an answer to that.
这整个课程本质上就是对它进行回答
How can we raise that base level?
我们如何提升基准水平?
One of the things is coping,putting ourselves on the line.
一个方法是去面对 把自己置于风险之上
And the reason why coping,
我们这么做的原因
why putting ourselves on the line yields positive
是因为这样能产生积极的影响
results in terms of the base level of wellbeing going up,
结果 幸福基准会上升
meaning still the ups and downs,
意思是仍然有起有落
but ups and downs looking this way
但起伏是像这样斜线上升的
as opposed to around a straight line
而不是在一条直线上或者
or a parallel line is that when we cope,we see ourselves coping,
平行线上徘徊 我们去面对时能想象我们的行动
we see ourselves trying and through self perception theory,
想象自己在努力 通过自我知觉理论
we derive certain conclusions about ourselves:
我们对自己做某种总结
oh,I must be courageous;
我一定很勇敢
oh,I must be a person who has high self esteem;
我一定是自尊心强的人
oh,I must be a person who has a strong desire to succeed
我一定是非常渴望成功的人
and so on and so on.
等等
And then we derive conclusions about ourselves in the same way
然后我们给自己做出的结论
that we derive conclusions about other people.
就像我们给他人的结论一样
That is self-perception theory.
这就是自我知觉理论
The second reason is that once we started failing more often,
第二个原因是一旦我们经常经历失败
we realized that actually it's not that bad,
我们会意识到那其实并不那么糟糕
it's not what we make it out to be.
不像我们想象的那么糟
The pain that in our minds we associate with failure
我们脑中想象的失败的痛苦
is far greater that the actual pain of failure when that comes.
比实际的痛苦要多得多
Maybe not initially when it happens,but after a while;
也许不是即时的 而是稍后才感受到
and then we recover again,and we see,oh,I can deal with it,
当我们恢复后 就知道我能应付它
I must be a person with resilience.
我一定是一个有适应力的人
And finally,there is more success as a result of coping.
最终 努力去面对后会有更多成功
Learn to fail,or fail to learn,
学习失败 或在失败中学习
there is no other way to succeed.
成功没有其他途径
So what I want to move on to now and just finish up on
我现在要说的是
is how do we become more of an optimistic.
我们如何变得更乐观
So we talked about the virtues,we talked about longevity,
我们谈过优点 谈过长寿
people who are optimistic actually live longer.
乐观的人实际上活得更久
We talked about higher levels of success,
我们谈过更高水平的成功
higher levels of happiness,more likely to overcome depression.
更高程度的快乐更能克服忧郁
People who are optimistic
乐观的人
are eight times less likely to be depressed;
患上忧郁的机会是八分之一
they are much more likely to be happy.
他们会更快乐
And again,optimism as an interpretation style,
再说一遍 乐观是指诠释的方式
not as a Pollyannaish feel-good kind of approach.
而不是盲目地自我感觉良好的方式
So how do we become more of an optimism?
我们如何变得更加乐观?
I want to talk about three techniques.
我想谈谈三个方法
First is to take action,to just do it,
首先是采取行动 尽管去做
to put ourselves on the line.
把自己置于风险之上
Second,I'm going to talk about the power of imagination,
第二点 我要讲想象力
visualization,many of you are familiar with that,
形象化的力量 你们许多人熟悉这点
especially athletes as,as a technique.
尤其对运动员而言 作为一项技巧
So we'll talk about that technique.
我们要谈论这个技巧
And finally,cognitive therapy,
最后一点是认知疗法
which at least according to research,is the most successful,
至少研究表明 是当今最成功的
most effective therapeutic intervention out there today,
最有效的治疗干预手段
so we'll talk about some of the basics and summarize those.
我们要讲一些基本要素并进行归纳
So let me begin with action,
我们先说行动
this is based on research by Albert Bendura,
这是基于Albert Bendura的研究
you'll read about self-efficacy,
你们会了解到自我效能
his concept basically the idea of having strong believes
他的基本概念上是要有坚定的信念
and he just made it more academic,
他将它描述得更学术化
more scientific and researched for many years
更科学化 并研究了数年
and we talked about many benefits of self efficacy.
我们谈过自我效能的许多益处
What Bendura is coming out against in much of his work
Bendura所做的大部分工作是反对
is what has become known as the self esteem movement,
人们称为“自尊运动”的活动
or he's coming against
或者说他反对的是
what has become known as feel good movement.
被称为“感觉良好运动”的活动
Alright,so tell a child how great they are,
所谓的 告诉小孩他们有多好
how wonderful they are.
他们有多棒
Standing in front of a mirror every morning and tell yourself:
每天早上站在镜子前对自己说
hi,gorgeous ten times,and then you will be more successful,
“你好精神”十遍 你将更成功
your self esteem will be high and you'll be gorgeous.
你的自尊会提升 你会变得很好
It doesn't work,believe me it doesn't work.
这不管用 相信我 这不管用
I've tried everything. The thing though is that very often,
我都试过 实际上经常
it actually hurts in the long term,it actually hurts self esteem
事实上长期以往会造成伤害 会伤到自尊
it actually hurts the motivation of students
它实际伤害了那些学生的积极性
who are constantly told you are wonderful,
他们经常被夸奖说"你们很棒"
you are terrific no matter what.
"你们都很了不起"
And we'll talk about how we can be more discerning with praise,
我们会讲如何对赞扬更有辨识力
how we can praise in the right way
如何正确地赞扬
when we talked about the work of Carol Dweck
在我们过几周谈论Carol Dweck
on mindsets in a few weeks.
关于心态的文章的时候
In the meantime,what Bendura showed,
同时Bendura表明
what Carol Dweck showed,
Carol Dweck表明
what many others showed was that it's not enough,
还有其他许多人都表明 这还不够
very often,its even detrimental to just give the,you know,
通常情况 只给你积极的言论 积极的肯定
positive,positive talk,the positive affirmation.
无论来自外部或内部
Whether it comes from the outside or from the inside,
这甚至是有害的
maybe part of the equation,certainly can't be all.
这也许其中的一部分 但不是全部
What Bendura is saying,that rather than talk,we need action.
Bendura说的是 我们需要的是行动而不是空谈
We need to put hard work into whatever it is,
我们对任何事都要付出努力
we want to be more confident about,and we need to cope.
我们想变得更自信 就需要去应对
We need to put ourselves on the line. Very simple! Why?
我们要把自己置于风险之上 很简单 为什么?
Because hard work and coping inevitably leads to success,
因为努力和面对必然能获得成功
more success at least than we had before,
至少比以前
when we didn't act and we didn't cope.
以前不行动 不去面对时要成功
So even if it's a little bit,in and of itself contributes,
即使只是一点点成功的贡献
that success contributes to our self-efficacy,
也有助于提高自我效能
to our self confidence. And then,that self confidence in turns,
有助于增加自信 而自信反过来
in turn motivates us to work harder.
反过来激励我们更努力
We started to believe ourselves more.
我们开始更加相信自己
Now,this is a very simple model,I mean,anyone you know,
这是个很简单的模型 我是说任何人
the five year old could draw that model.
一个五岁小孩都能做出那个模型
However think about the implications for our lives,
然而考虑到对我们生活的影响
think about the implications for education,
考虑到对教育的影响
do we just tell students constantly you're terrific,
我们应该仅是对学生不停地说你们很棒
you're wonderful,you're great,or do we like Marva Collins,
你们真厉害 还是应该像Marva Collins那样
make them actually work hard so that they succeed more,
让他们努力奋斗获得更多成功
so that they see themselves going back to self conception theory,
让他们想象自己回归自我概念理论
see themselves working hard,
想象自己努力奋斗
see themselves putting themselves on the line,
想象自己投身其中
coping and failing,and getting up again.
面对失败 重新站起
It works also in a similar way to our physical immune system.
它和我们身体免疫系统运作方式相同
You know when we get sick,when we get ill,
当我们身体不适 当我们生病时
our body sense anti-bodies
我们的身体感应到抗体
and we actually become immune to whatever it is that we had.
我们实际上会免疫得过的病
So our body become immunize through failure.
我们的身体通过失败获得免疫力
Same on the psychological level,failure is underrated.
在心理层面也相同 失败会被低估
You know one of the things that I wish for you,
我希望你们拥有的东西之一
and I mean it genuinely.
我是很真挚的
One of the things that I wish for you is that you fail more.
希望你们能多经历失败
I'm not saying it ingest,I really do.
我不是随便说说 我真这么想的
And,coupled with that,I hope that when you fail,
另外 我希望当你们失败时
you will also learn to interpret it in a different way
你们也能学习用不同的方式去诠释
than most of us usually interpret failure.
而不像大多数人那样诠释失败
'Cause there is no other way to succeed,
因为没有别的方式取得成功
there is no other way for growth,
成长的途径只有这一条
it's an elusion that a life looks like this,
像这样的生活 只是在逃避
we will talk about it much more
我们会继续谈这个
when we talk about perfectionism.
当我们谈论完美主义时
A healthy life,a real life,
健康的生活 真实的生活
and a happy life ultimately looks like this,
快乐的生活基本都看起来像这样
a spiral with ups and downs,not as a straight line.
一个带起伏的螺旋 不是一条直线
When we see ourselves cope,when we see ourselves work hard,
当我们看到自己去面对 努力奋斗时
we derive conclusions about ourselves,
我们对自己做出结论
our self confidence goes up,our motivation goes up,
我们的自信增长 我们的动力增加
our belief goes up and so on and so on
我们的信仰上升 等等
in an upward spiral of growth.
以一个上升螺旋的趋势发展
Soren Kierkegaard: "To dare is to lose one's footing momentarily.
Soren Kierkegaard说过"勇于冒险或许会一时失足
Not to dare is to lose oneself."
却步不前则会迷失自我”
To lose one's footing temporarily is the failure
当我们去面对 去尝试 满怀期望时
that comes inevitably when we cope,when we try,
一时失足而导致失败
when we have high expectations. Not to dare is to lose oneself,
不可避免 而我们不去应对 选择逃避
that is when we don't cope,when we avoid.
却步不前则会迷失自我
Because this model also works the other way around.
因为这个模型倒过来也成立
When we constantly avoid challenges,
当我们不断地逃避挑战
when we constantly shone difficult experiences,
当我们总能处理好困难经历
when we don't give ourselves the permission to fail,
当我们不允许自己失败时
a downward spiral is created,in terms of our self esteem,
会形成一个向下的螺旋 影响自尊
in terms of our success,in terms of our well being.
我们的成功和幸福
Second technique: imagining success.
第二个技巧 想象成功
Now there's one thing I want to share with you,
有件事我想和你们分享
I'm a little bit nervous about sharing it
要和你们分享让我有点紧张
but I'll do it anyway,you know,since we've opened up,
但既然已经说开了 无论如何我都会说
especially last time was a real milestone in our relationship.
尤其上节课真是我们关系中的转折点
I'm gonna to tell you something but please don't tell anyone,
我要告诉你们些事 但别告诉别人
you know,especially don't tell any of my clients
尤其别告诉我的客户
or potential clients in the future.
或将来的潜在客户
I get really nervous before lectures.
我演讲前会非常紧张
I get very nervous,in fact for me,
我会很紧张 其实对我而言
whenever I stand in front of a large audience,
我无论何时站在许多观众面前
there're butterflies in my stomach.
心里会七上八下的
And it's very difficult for me
我觉得这很难
when I talk about large audience its anything above five.
我说的许多观众是指多于五人
So,this is a real challenge,
所以这是个真正的挑战
it's a real challenge when I talk to clients.
当我和客户们聊天时是个挑战
And this is been a challenge since the dash I decided
这一直是一个挑战 从我决定
that I want to be a teacher and I decided
当一名教师的那一刻起 当我听说了
that I want to be a teacher when I heard Marva Collins,
Marva Collins的事迹时就决定成为一名老师
and I said: this is my calling. And here is what happened then.
我说"这就是对我的召唤" 后来我就成为了老师
I said,how can I be a successful teacher and effective teacher
我曾说 "如果我在人们面前会这么紧张
if I get so nervous when I stand in front of an audience?
我要如何成为成功而有效率的老师?"
And remember the three components of success,
记得成功的三要素
the secret of success? It was optimism,believe in oneself;
成功的秘密? 是乐观和自信
it was passion,loving what you do; and it was hard work.
是热情 热爱你所做的 还有努力奋斗
So I had two of the three components.
我有其中两个要素
I worked extremely hard,in fact my motto has become,
我非常努力 实际上我的座右铭
one that I got from Professor Richard Hackman,
来自Richard Hackman教授
as my thesis advisor as an undergrad here.
他是我在这里读本科时的论文导师
And,what he said,he's a phenomenal teacher,
他是一个非凡的教师
and what he said when he goes into a classroom is the following:
他走进教室后会说
prepare,prepare,prepare,and then be spontaneous.
准备 再准备...然后顺其自然
So I followed his advise,now I read over my notes,
所以我遵照他的建议 我仔细看教案
I have all the notes written down and then I can let go.
我准备好所有教案 然后不再去想它
So I prepare a lot,I have the hard work,not a problem.
我准备得很充足 我很努力 没问题
I have the passion,I love learning,
我有热情 我爱学习
it's the most important thing,professionally in my life.
这是我职业生命中最重要的事
But I lacked the third thing,I lacked optimism,
但我缺少第三样 缺少乐观
and I lacked confidence. And then I asked myself:
缺少自信 我问我自己
how can I raise the third components
我要怎样提高第三个要素
because it is important component of wellbeing,
因为这是幸福的一个重要部分
remember the research on athletes?
记得对运动员的研究吗?
56% of the variance is accounted of success,
56%的成功
is accounted for by the sense of optimism or belief in yourself.
是源自乐观主义或自信
Remember the John Carter study? Twenty years along
还记得John Carter二十年前的研究吗
when you look at Harvard Business School graduates,
关于哈佛大学商学院毕业生的
one of the two components that
将最成功的学生和其他人区分开的
differentiated the most successful from the rest,
两要素之一
one of them was belief in themselves,confidence.
一个是相信自己 自信
It's an important component of success and I lacked it.
这是成功的一个重要因素 而我缺少它
So what did I do? I went back and thought about
我怎么办? 我回想到
what happened when I played squash,
打壁球时的事情
what my coaches used to teach me,and that was visualization.
我的教练过去教育我要形象化
And I started reading up and
我开始阅读这方面内容
when I looking at literature and there's a lot of research on it,
我查看文献时 看到很多关于这方面的研究
it actually started off centuries ago in religious practices,
实际上在几世纪前宗教实践时就出现
was brought to athletics through east European athletes
被东欧运动员引入到体育运动中
who would imagine themselves,say,
他们会想象自己 比如
running around the track and then standing on the podium,
在跑道上跑然后站在颁奖台上
receiving the gold medal.
领取金牌
And more and more psychologists started to implement it.
越来越多的心理学家把它应用起来
Sales people use it very effectively,
销售人员很有效地使用它
seeing themselves actually striking the deal,
想象自己真的谈成了生意
going through with it,doing it and succeeding.
经历困难 去做 并获得成功
And that made it much more likely to come true.
那让它更有可能成为现实
The question is why? What's the mechanism behind visualization?
为什么?形象化背后有什么原理?
Why is it so important? Why is it so good?
为什么这么重要?为什么它这么好?
Why is it so effective?
为什么它这么有效?
Why it being used so widely and successfully?
为什么被这么广泛而成功地使用?
And the answer goes back to the structure of our brains.
答案归结到我们大脑的结构上
This is research done by the head of psychology department,
这个研究是由心理系主任
Professor Steven Kosslyn.
Stephen Kosslyn教授做的
What he shows was that when we see something,
他说当我们看某样东西时
so let's say I'm looking at my hand right now.
比如说我现在看着我的手
There are certain neurons in my brain that are firing,
我大脑中的某些神经元被激活
that actually take on the shape of this hand.
实际上记住了这只手的形状
My visual cortex,the back.
我的视觉皮质 后部
Now,
现在
if I close my eyes and imagine that I'm looking at this hand,
如果我闭上眼想象我在看这只手
even if it's not here,if I imagine that I look at this hand,
即使它不在那 如果我想象看这只手
the exact same neurons are firing. In other words,
相同的神经元会激活 换句话说
my brain does not know the difference
我的大脑无法区别
between the real thing and the imaginary thing.
真实的事物和想象的事物
Which explains why dreams can be so vivid,
这解释了为什么梦境会那么生动
n the middle of the night,pitch dark,
在漆黑的深夜
and you are dreaming about mid of the day,
你正梦到中午
walking around the yard.
在院子里散步
Our imagination,
我们的想象
least for the brain is no different than the real thing.
至少对于大脑而言与现实没有区别
Now,when I imagine success,what happens in a sense is
当我想象成功时 从某种意义上说
that I'm creating a simulator for my mind.
我在为大脑做一个模拟
And I'm in a sense fooling my mind into thinking
我可以说是在欺骗大脑认为
that this is the real thing.
这是真的事情
My mind doesn't know the difference between the two.
我的大脑不知道两者的区别
Subconscious mind doesn't know the difference
潜意识无法区分
between the real thing and the imaginary thing.
真实的事物和假想的事物
Now if I imagine success over and over again in my mind,
如果我在脑海中反复想象着成功
remember what the mind does not like is inconsistency.
记住大脑不喜欢不一致性
In other words,
换句话说
if I create success in my imagination and I persist with it,
如果我想象着成功并坚持不懈
not just visualize it once or twice,but over and over again,
不止设想一两次 而是一次又一次
the mind doesn't like inconsistencies.
大脑不喜欢不一致性
And therefore,it will bring up the external reality
因此它会让外部现实
to match this internal schema.
和内心的想象相符
Why? Because the mind doesn't know
为什么?因为大脑不知道
the difference in the real thing and imaginary thing.
真实的事物和假想的事物间的区别
Just like Thomas,
就像Thomas
just like Roger Bannister run the four minutes a mile
就像Roger Bannister四分钟内跑完一英里
and after that,after that what happened was
在那之后
that everyone had a different schema:
每个人都有了和以往不同的想法
Oh,four minutes a mile is possible and 37 runners run it,
四分钟跑完一英里是可能的 然后37人成功了
over 300 runners run it the following year.
第二年超过300人实现了
Because they had a difference schema:
因为他们有了不同的想法
we can do exactly the same thing through the simulator.
我们可以通过场景模拟做到同样的事情
Cause the mind doesn't know the difference
因为大脑无法区分
in the real thing and the imaginary thing.
真实的事物和假想的事物
Doesn't work all the time,
不是总能成功
doesn't work a hundred percent of the time,
不是百分之一百管用
but it works a great deal.
但很多时候都很管用
What I do every time when I give a lecture is visualize.
我每次演讲总要设想一下
I imagine myself stand in front of the audience,
我想象自己站在观众前
calm,excited,passionate.
冷静 激动 热情
And then when I go into the real thing,
当我正式开始演讲时
now I don't know if it is the real thing or I'm imaging,
现在我不知道这是真的还是想象的
but I assume it's the real thing.
但我假设这是真的
When I go into the real thing,I do feel that.
正式开始演讲时 我确实有同样的感受
I still get nervous,I still get anxious,
我仍然会紧张 仍然会焦虑
but it's a healthy,excitement.
但这是健康的兴奋
Raising my levels of beliefs,levels of confidence by practicing,
通过练习提高了我的信心和自信水平
just like a flight... a pilot,you would hope...
就像一个...一个飞行员
would practice in a simulator
会希望能在模拟环境中先练习
before they take you on across the Atlantic.
然后再飞越大西洋
The mind as a simulator,this is why it works.
思想是个模拟器 所以它能管用
The key here,this is a mistake that many people make,
关键是... 这有一个许多人都犯过的错误
whether it's athletics or whether it's in the,
无论是运动员或是...
a lot of the self-help books that talked about visualizations.
许多关于形象化自励书籍中的记载
The key is to focused not just on the destination,
关键是不仅仅只关注结果
Shelley Taylor,UCLA,
加州大学洛杉矶分校的Shelley Taylor
did this research where she divided students in two random groups
做了研究 把学生随机分成两组
One student imaging themselves getting an A on the exam
一个学生想象在考试中得到A
and imagine it over and over again.
一遍遍地这样想象
The second group,imaging themselves getting an A
第二组想象他们得到A
but also saw themselves work and persist in the library,
但也想象他们在图书馆坚持努力
prepare for it,and then,get to that final A.
为考试做准备 最后得到了A
The second group that imaging both the journey
第二组想象了过程
and the destination was much more successful,
和结果 他们更加成功
much better result in the exam.
考试成绩更好
So visualize the journey as well as the destination,
想象过程和结果
this is your response paper for this week,
这是你们这周的作业
to visualize both your destination of getting there,
想象你们实现目的
your journey of getting there,as well as the destination itself.
你们实现目的的过程以及目的本身
Arguably,the most,or certainly one of the most influential
史上最有影响力的演讲 或者之一
speeches of all time was Martin Luther King's I have a dream.
是马丁路德金的《我有一个梦想》
I've read this speech more than dozens of times.
这个演讲我听了不下12次
Why? Because beyond its beauty,its rhythm and its importance,
为什么?因为除了它很美 押韵和重要性之外
it also captures what is means,
也表达了它的意图
what it means to create an image of success.
它的意图就是描绘出一幅成功的画面
'Cause this is what he did for this country
因为这是他为这个国家做的
and defined generations to come.
并为后来人所定义的远景
So first of all,I want to read some excerpts from it.
因此首先 我想从中摘录几句
It is about visualizating a better future,
是对一个更美好的未来的想象
and he says it explicitly,doesn't hide it.
他说得很明确 没有隐藏
He says: "I have a dream,I say to you today my friends,
"我有一个梦想 朋友们 今天我对你们说
so even though we face the difficulties of today and tomorrow
在此时此刻 我们虽然遭受种种困难和挫折
I still have a dream.
我仍然有一个梦想
It is a dream deeply rooted in the America dream."
这个梦想是深深扎根于美国的梦想中的"
This is all about imagination,
这都是关于想象
but through the imagination he created a better reality.
但通过想象他创建了更好的现实
Look at how he talks about the process;
看他如何谈论这个过程
he doesn't talk just about the outcome:
他不是仅仅谈到结果
we want equality at the end.
我们希望最后达到平等
He talks about how we will get to this outcome.
他谈的是我们如何获得这个结果
So let me read you a couple of excerpts:
让我读几句摘录的句子
"This is no time to engage in the luxury of cooling off
"现在绝非侈谈冷静下来
or to take the tranquilizing drug of gradualism."
或服用渐进主义的镇静剂的时候"
How beautiful! I mean,what he's saying here is,
多优美 我是说 他这里说的是
let's not just sit here and wait
我们别只坐着等待
and imagine that things will happen,
想象会发生的事情
let's do something,let's also have a process.
让我们做些事情 让我们也着眼于过程
And he says explicitly:
他明确地说
"In the process of gaining our rightful place,
"在争取合法地位的过程中
we must not be guilty of wrongful deeds."
我们不要采取错误的做法"
So here he's talking about advice,of suggestions,advice,
这里他在提建议 提议
what we should and shouldn't do along the way.
这个过程中什么该做 什么不该做
"We must forever conduct our struggle
"我们斗争时必须永远举止得体
on the high play of dignityand discipline. We must not allow
纪律严明 我们不能容许
our creative protest to degenerate into physical violence."
我们的具有崭新内容的抗议蜕变为暴力行动"
He's describing a process.
他在描述一个过程
"Again and again,we must rise to the majestic heights
"我们要不断地升华到
of meeting physical force with soul force."
以精神力量对付物质力量的崇高境界中去"
Another thing that we need to do
我们要做的另一件事
when we imagine success is to make is as real as possible
当我们想象成功时 尽可能逼真点
by involving as many senses as we can. Why?
尽量使人有所感受 为什么?
Because the more senses we can imagine,
因为感受越真实
the more our mind is fooled to believe that it is the real thing.
我们的大脑就越相信这是真实的
Once again,Martin Luther King does this beautifully.
再次 马丁路德金这点上也做得非常漂亮
Let me read you a few excerpts:
让我读几句摘录的句子
"We will not be satisfied until justice rolls down like waters
"我们将来也不满足 除非正义和公正犹如江海之波涛
and righteousness like a mighty stream."
汹涌澎湃 滚滚而来"
I mean,you can feel the water,you can feel that stream,
你们能感受到那江海波涛
you can see it,you can visualize it.
你们能看到 能想象到
"Or,let us not seek to satisfy our thirst for freedom
"我们不要为了满足对自由的渴望
by drinking from the cup of bitterness and hatred."
而抱着苦味和仇恨之杯痛饮"
He's employing test,bitterness,equaling with hatred.
他引入了味觉 苦味等同于仇恨
People connect to it,making it real,concrete.
人们会联想到它 让它真实 具体化
"One day right there in Alabama little black boys and black girls
"有朝一日 阿拉巴马州的黑人男孩和女孩
will be able to join hands with
将能与白人男孩和女孩情同骨肉
little white boys and white girls as sisters and brothers."
携手并进"
I mean,you can see that circle of the kids holding hand,
你能想象到孩子们手拉手围成圈
again making it real,you can visualize it,you see it.
再次让它变得真实 你可以想象到 看到它
By the way,these are the characteristics of all great speeches.
顺便说下 这是所有著名演讲的特征
They are not abstract,
它们不是抽象的
look at the great communicator Ronald Reagan.
看看那"伟大的沟通者"罗纳德里根
Look at Kennedy.
看肯尼迪
They gave amazing speeches because they created a picture,
他们演讲很精彩 因为他们创造了一幅图画
they involve the senses,they created a picture of success.
他们利用了感官 创造了一幅成功的画面
"I have a dream that one day even the state of Mississippi,
"我梦想有一天 甚至连密西西比州
a state sweltering with the heat of injustice,
这个正义匿迹 压迫成风
weltering with the heat of oppression will be transformed
如同沙漠般的地方
into an oasis of freedom and justice."
也将变成自由和正义的绿洲"
You can actually feel the heat,
你真的能感受到那种酷热
you can actually feel the sweat that he's describing.
你真的能感受到他描述的那种汗如雨下的感觉
This is what makes good,successful images.
这描绘出了一幅好的 成功的画面
This is what makes great speeches.
这让演讲变得很精彩
And finally,it's about evoking emotions.
最后 要唤起情绪
You don't want just make it cognitive exercise,
你不想只是做一个认知练习
you wanna really be excited about what you are doing,
你要对自己正在做的感到非常兴奋
or else it will fall flat. Nothing,no change will happen.
否则将会失败 什么都没有改变
Again,the connection between the words emotion and motion:
这些词语间的联系 情感和行动
without emotion,there is no motion.
没有情感就没有行动
If you want to move yourself or others,
如果你想让自己或别人行动起来
you need to evoke emotions.
你得引起情感共鸣
Let's look at,just a minute,of that historical speech.
让我们稍微看看那段历史性的演讲
"From every mountain side,let freedom ring!
"让自由之声响彻每个山岗
And if America is to be a great nation,this must become true.
如果美国要成为一个伟大的国家 这个梦想必须实现
And so
所以
let freedom ring from the prodigious hilltops of New Hampshire.
让自由之声从新罕布什尔州的巍峨的崇山峻岭响起来
Let freedom ring from the mighty mountains of New York.
让自由之声从纽约州的崇山峻岭响起来
Let freedom ring from the heightening Alleghenies of Pennsylvania
让自由之声从宾夕法尼亚州的阿勒格尼山}上响起来
Let freedom ring from the snow-capped Rockies of Colorado.
让自由之声从科罗拉多州冰雪覆盖的落基山响起来
Let freedom ring from the curvaceous slopes of California.
让自由之声从加利福尼亚州蜿蜒的群峰响起来
But not only that:
不仅如此
Let freedom ring from Stone Mountain of Georgia.
还要让自由之声从佐治亚州的石岭响起来
Let freedom ring from Lookout Mountain of Tennessee.
让自由之声从田纳西州的了望山响起来
Let freedom ring from every hill and molehill of Mississippi.
让自由之声从密西西比的每一座丘陵响起来
From every mountainside,let freedom ring.
让自由之声从每一片山坡响起来
And when this happens,when we allow freedom ring,
当这成真 我们使自由之声响彻时
when we let it ring from every village and every hamlet,
当我们让自由之声从每一个大小村庄
from every state and every city,we will be able to speed up
每一个州和每一个城市响起来时 我们将能够加速
that day when all of God's children,black men and white men,
这一天的到来 那时 上帝的所有儿女 黑人和白人
Jews and Gentiles,Protestants and Catholics,
犹太教徒和非犹太教徒 基督教徒和天主教徒
will be able to join hands and sing
都将手携手 合唱一首
in the words of the old Negro spiritual,
古老的黑人灵歌
"Free at last! Free at last!
"终于自由啦！终于自由啦！
Thank God Almighty,we are free at last!"
感谢全能的上帝，我们终于自由啦"
I've seen this as I said dozens of times,every time excitement.
我看过十几遍 每次看都很激动
Imagine if you said at the end: Free at last! Free at last!
假想你最后说 终于自由啦 终于自由啦
God Almighty,free at last! Would that have the same effect?
全能的上帝 终于自由啦 有同样效果吗
Boring,dry,you have to evoke emotions to create motion,
无聊 枯燥 你必须引发情感来创造行动
whether is in our imagination or in a speech to the nation
不论是在想象中或是对全国人演讲
Another technique...Another technique that I'd like to talk about,
另一个技巧 另一个我要说的技巧
the third technique. So the first one was: work,
第三个技巧 第一个是 努力行动起来
put yourself on the line,cope,invest.
投入其中 去面对
The second: use your imagination,
第二个 使用想象力
use the simulator that you have right here,
使用思想的模拟器
one of the most if not the most powerful simulator we know of.
一个我们所知的最强大的模拟器
The third is cognitive therapy.
第三是 认知疗法
Cognitive therapy has been used very successfully over the last,
认知疗法已被成功地运用四十多年
over forty years,Martin Seligman was one of the founders
Martin Seligman是认知疗法的
of the cognitive therapy approach.
创始人之一
He studied with,with Beck,
他和Beck一起做研究
who was the official founder of this technique in this approach.
Beck是这技巧的正式创始人
And what cognitive therapy is about is the following.
认知疗法的内容如下
Its basic premise is that thoughts drive emotion.
它的基本前提是思想驱动情感
So for example: there is an external event.
比如 外部发生一件事
I perceive that event,
我感知到那件事
and what I do then after I perceive that event,
我感知那件事后的行动是
there is evaluation of that event,
对那事进行评估
in other words,a thought about that event.
也就是对那件事进行思考
And then,as a result of that thought,that evokes an emotion.
思考后就唤起了情感
So for example,an event,a lion is running toward me,
比如 事件 有只狮子向我奔来
my evaluation: oh my god,he's gonna eat me.
我的评估 天 它要吃掉我
The emotion: fear,and that of course leads to motion,
引发的情感是恐惧 然后自然就导致行动
run away or stand up bravely and fight the lion.
逃跑或勇敢地和狮子搏斗
Or,another one: I see an event,
或另一个例子 一个事件
a gorgeous woman walking down the street,my evaluation:
一个美女在街上走 我的评估
oh,it's my gorgeous wife,and the emotion:love.
是我的漂亮太太 引发的情感是爱
Event,evaluation,thought,emotion,
事件 评估 思考 情感
and then that leads to action.
然后导致行动
What cognitive therapy says is that if we want to change emotions
认知疗法认为如果我们想改变情感
whether it's of depression,whether it's of anxiety,
无论是忧郁或焦虑
where we need to intervene is here,
我们要干预的是
is that the level of evaluation and the level of thought.
评估和想法层面
And if we can change that,we also change our emotion.
如果能改变这个 我们的情感也随着改变
Specifically,what cognitive therapy saying is that
特别地 认知疗法认为
we need to restore sense of rationality,
我们要恢复理性意识
we need to restore the real,it's certainly not saying,
我们要恢复真实 当然这不是说
let's say I have a,you know,
比如 我有
a very important try out coming up and I get nervous.
一个非常重要的试镜 我很紧张
Cognitive therapy is not saying stop feeling nervous,
认知疗法不是说停止紧张
let's change your evaluation or your thoughts,
我们改变你的评估 或你的想法
because that's natural or I stand in front of a lion.
因为那是自然的 又或者我站在狮子面前
It's natural,it's important,it's healthy to experience fear.
感到害怕是自然的 重要的 健康的体验
But
但是
what it is saying is that sometimes our thoughts are irrational,
它说的是我们的想法有时是荒谬的
and we'll mention that last time,for example,
我们上节课提到过 比如
I don't do well on one test
我有一次考试成绩不好
and immediately I classified myself as stupid
我立刻认为自己很笨
or the fact that I will never succeed in tests again.
或认为我考试永远不会取得好成绩
Or,you know,I asked someone out and he says no,
或者 我约别人出去 被拒绝了
and suddenly nobody wants me.
突然觉得没有人需要我
That event led to an irrational thought,
这个事件引发一个荒谬的想法
irrational evaluation of the situation.
对情景的荒谬评估
It was just once,it was temporary,
那只是一次性的 短暂的失败
and that led to difficult emotions such as resignation:
而那会引发不好的情感 比如放弃
nobody will ever want me again.
没人会再需要我了
And what cognitive therapy does is just restore
而认知疗法做的是恢复理性
that rationality by saying: yeah,it hurts,it's tough,
通过说“是的 这很伤人 很痛苦”
but,you know they are,what? 3200 other men at Harvard.
但你知道 哈佛还有3200个其他男人
Cognitive therapy has been shown to be extremely effective,
认知疗法极其有效
more effective than any of the other intervention,
比其他干预手段都更有效
the jury still out
虽然它对于
when it comes to extreme cases of psychopathology,
极端棘手的精神病理学病例不太管用
but in terms of most psychopathologies,most anxiety,
但对于大多数精神病理学病例 多数的焦虑症状
most depression,it has been shown to be the most successful,
多数的忧郁症状 它已经被证明是最成功的
and it works the fastest. Not the only thing that works,
且起效最快的方法 它不仅有用
but it works the best and much more promptly
而且最有效 最迅速
than the other interventions.
相对其他干预而言
On the whole,not right for everyone,but for most people.
总体上 不是人人有效 但大多数有效
And finally,and this is the important thing we can learn it.
最后 这是我们能学会的重要的内容
So we talk about right?
我们提过
The five-year Cambridge Somerville study that failed.
五年的剑桥-萨默维尔研究失败了
Well,Karen Reivich teaches these cognitive skills
Karen Reivich在一个两周的项目中
in a two week program.
教授这些认知技巧
And that two week program helps kids in inner cities,
那个两周的项目旨在帮助市中心的
at risk population,
危险人群中的孩子们
reduce the likelihood of falling into the trap of depression,
降低陷入忧郁和吸毒困境的可能性
of drug abuse,increases the likelihood of wellbeing
增加幸福的可能性
and success in the long term just as a result
这个为期两周的认知疗法或技巧的课程
of two weeks teaching them cognitive therapy or these techniques,
结果在长远看来是成功的
so it's an accquired skill
所以这是可以学到的技能
and this is the important thing about it.
这就是重要之处
That doesn't mean its easy,
不是说很容易
doesn't mean you're just gonna hear a lecture now for the,
不是说你听了一次课
the next ten minutes I'm gonna describe some of the ideas
下面的十分钟我要讲一些概念
and that's gonna change your life. You need to apply it,
就能改变你的生活 你要运用它
and you are going to apply it in the next two,
你们将要把它运用到之后两节
next two classes,but you need to do more than that.
之后两节课中 但你们要做的更多
So let me share with you a summary of cognitive therapy
我给你们讲下认知疗法的概要
and this...the 3Ms is my acronym.
这三个M是首字母缩写
And what I did there was to put together essentially the work
我所做的是从本质上把
of Karen Reivich whom I just mentioned,
我刚提到的Karen Reivich的成果
the work of Martin Seligman,
Martin Seligman的成果
the work of Aaron Beck Seligman's teacher
Seligman的老师Aaron Beck的成果
and the work of David Burns. Some of you may heard of him,
还有David Burns的成果 你们也许有人知道他
The Feeling Good Handbook,who is also a student of Aaron Beck.
《好心情手册》的作者 也是Aaron Beck的学生
So this is putting together their work
把他们的成果结合起来
into 3Ms subdivided each into 2 suggestions.
成为三个M 每个M有二个建议
They're inter connected as you'll see.
你们会看到它们互相有联系
It's not a very clear distinction. However what you'll notice is
区别不怎么明显 但你们会注意到
you could usually relate to one or two of the 3Ms.
你们总能联系上三M中的一两个
Things that you do yourself. So beyond the lookout ask yourself:
在你们行动之前先问自己
"Where do I distort the reality?
“我在哪处扭曲了事实?
Where do I have distortion in terms of evaluation?
我在评估方面 或者
In terms of my thought?"
想法方面哪里歪曲了事实?”
That lead to certain negative emotions that are unnecessary,
导致了某些不必要的消极情绪
because if I restore rationality
因为如果我恢复理性
I will not feel the same emotion to the same degree.
我就感觉不到同样程度的情感
So ask yourself when you look through the 3Ms.
所以当你们学习三个M的时候问自己
The 3Ms...essentially the 3 traps of irrational thoughts.
三个M指的是非理性想法的三个陷阱
The first one is magnifying.
第一个是放大
It's exaggerating something that happens. For example,
就是夸大发生的事情 比如
you know induction is something very natural.
归纳法是天生的本能
A kid sees this and will call it a stool
一个孩子看到这个 会叫它凳子
and then they see another stool in the bar
然后他们在酒吧看到另一张凳子
when they go out at the age of one
当他们一岁时出去
and then they see another stool. After they see 20 stools
再看到另一张凳子 看过20张凳子后
they begin to form a concept they induce that this is a stool.
开始形成一个观念 认为这东西就是凳子
And now they see one even one
现在他们看到一张
that they have never seen before they know what it is.
以前从没见过的凳子 他们也知道是它什么
Just like I see a person in the street
就像我看见一个人在街上
whom I never encounter before I know this is a person,
以前从没见过他 我知道这是个人
because I induce from all the other events
因为我从其他发生过的事件中
that happened before that this is also a person.
归纳出这个也是一个人
So that's induction. That's healthy. That's important.
这就是归纳法 是健康的 重要的
That's how we develop concepts and language.
我们就是这样形成观念和语言的
But sometimes we take this too far and we over generalize.
但有时我们做得过头 归纳过度了
Once again,I did poorly on the midterm...conclusion,
比如 我期中考成绩很差
generalization: I'm just not smart. I just can't succeed.
归纳为 我不聪明 我不能成功
Here is a student. Over generalization,the evaluation,
这个学生就是归纳过度了 他的评估
the thought,irrational.
他的想法是非理性的
Or he just said no to me. Everyone is gonna say no.
或他拒绝了我 因此大家都会拒绝我
instead of being realistic and saying,"wow,just look around.
而不是实事求是地说 "看看周围
There are so many wonderful and sensitive and caring men in 1504"
1504课堂上还有有很多帅哥"
So,another thing this is something we'll talk about a lot...
另一件事我们经常讨论的是
the All or Nothing approach. The All or Nothing...
全有或全无态度
we'll talk about it when we talk about perfectionism.
我们会在讲完美主义时讨论它
It's catastrophizing failure,
它是把失败小题大做
not seeing failure as an opportunity,
而不是把失败当做一次机遇
as a stepping stone but seeing it as the end of the world.
一个跳板 而是视之为世界末日
I got a B as a freshman. Now I'm going to be homeless.
我大一时得了B 现在要无家可归了
Not finding a job ever. All or Nothing.
永远找不到工作 全有或全无
Either straight As or complete failure.
要么全是A 要么就是彻底的失败
We'll talk about that a lot.
我们会多次提及它
Because it's one of the key elements that prevents us from coping
因为这是阻止我们去面对的一个关键要素
from putting ourselves on the line.
阻止我们投入进去
The other side of it,
它的另一面
which is actually other side of the same coin is minimizing.
同一个硬币的另一面 是极小化
This is something I do very often.
这是我经常做的
This is my trap that I still have to be aware of,
这是我仍要警惕的陷阱
I still think about today,
我至今仍会考虑
even though I became aware of it years ago.
虽然我几年前就注意到它了
Only now I catch myself doing it much promptly.
直到现在我才能够迅速醒觉自己在这么做
So the first idea of minimizing is
极小化的第一个概念是
what Karen Reivich calls tunnel vision.
Karen Reivich称之为“隧道视野”
For example,let's say I have 620 students in my class.
比如 我的课堂里有620个学生
And out of these 620 students 618 are engaged in the material.
620个中618个在看教材
One is looking at the ceiling,at the lights.
一个在看天花板 在看灯
And another one,out of the 620 students,is asleep.
620个中的另外一个在睡觉
Tunnel Vision is when I focus on that one person who is asleep.
隧道视野指的是当我关注那个睡觉的人
And I say to myself,
对自己说
" Wow,I'm giving boring,sleep inducing lectures."
“我的课肯定讲得让人无聊 犯困”
Or the other way around: I have 620 students,618 are asleep.
或反过来 620个学生中618个睡着
One is looking around. And one is going "wow!"
一个在开小差 一个听得十分入迷
and I only focus on that person and I say I'm a great lecturer.
我只关注那个人 我说我是个好讲师
I'm so inspiring.
我非常受鼓舞
Again,it's unrealistic. One way or the other. And
然而不管怎样这都是不现实的
what cognitive therapy does is bring realism into the equation.
认知疗法把现实主义引入这个等式
Again this is something I often fall into.
我也经常因此而困扰
And just recently I fell into this. And it happened...
我最近刚遇到这个情况
I know many of you saw the Jon Stewart show.
你们许多人看过Jon Stewart脱口秀
So what happened in the Jon Stewart show...he was so fast,
在Jon Stewart脱口秀中 他讲得太快
way too fast for me...I felt like I was 2 questions behind
对我而言超级快 我感觉就像落后了两拍
still contemplating and thinking and saying
还在深思和考虑着两个之前的问题
"well,this could be interesting research."
“这会是个很有趣的研究”
And Jon was...he was already 10 steps ahead.
而Jon已经领先了10步
So I fell behind and I felt slow.
我落后了 感觉很迟钝
And I also said something that I later regretted.
我也说了些后来让自己后悔的话
It was just one sentence.
只是一句话
No big deal. But that is what I focus on.
没什么大不了的 但我专注在这上面
You know I flew home after. I went back to Israel.
我后来飞回家 飞回以色列
The whole flight that what I was thinking of.
在飞机上我一直在想这事
Ignoring the other things.
忽略了其他的事情
You know the fact that 2 hours after the Jon Stewart show,
Jon Stewart脱口秀完了后二小时
the book became a best seller. Completely ignore that.
这本书成了最畅销书 我完全忽略了这个
Didn't exist as far as I was concerned.
我根本没去考虑那
It was just that one sentence. How could I say it?
我一直在想那句话 我怎么会说出来的?
Why didn't I prepare for it better? And so on.
为什么没有更好的准备? 等等
And then I suddenly said," Hey,wait a minute!" Tunnel Vision.
然后我突然说"等一下" 隧道视野
And I zoomed out. I looked at the bigger picture.
我把它缩小了 我把视野扩大
Then I said,"okay,so I said something that I regret. Big deal."
然后我说”我说了一句让我后悔的话 超赞啊”
You know. It's comedy. It's fun. So many people,
这是喜剧 很有趣 许多人在看
so many of your friends have watched and enjoyed it.
你的许多朋友都看过 都很喜欢
It was a great opportunity. I looked at the bigger picture.
这是个很好的机会 我看到了更大的方面
Gave myself the permission to be human.
允许自己做回一个人
To regret it.But then overall,
会感到后悔 但从总体上
I could see it in a much more rational light than before.
我能用比以前更理性的目光看待它
Big dealSo again,as I said,I still apply...I still use these ideas.
像我说的 我仍然在用这些想法
In the past,
过去
it would take me months to get over this one sentence.
我可能要花几个月才不会想这句话
Whereas now,zoom out. Evaluation thought,irrational.
但是现在 视野变窄 评估想法 非理性的影响
And recover much more promptly.
能更迅速地恢复
Dismissal of positives or negatives. So the person
消除积极或者消极的影响
who has tunnel vision doesn't see the other 618 people
有隧道视野的人不会去留意其他618个
who are engaged or asleep.
专心听课或睡觉的人
The person who dismiss the positives see those
忽视了积极面的人看到那些
but says they're unimportant; they are trivial in comparison to
但说他们不重要 它们很微不足道
how I just failed or what I just did wrong. So for example,
比起我的失败或我做的错事 比如
and this again,something that I...a trap that I often fall into.
我经常会遇到的一个困境
When I was a senior,I applied for fellowships
我大四时申请了奖学金
and I got a fellowship to go to Cambridge.
我得到去剑桥的奖学金
And I got the John Elliot Fellowship.
我得的是John Elliot奖学金
And there are 4 fellowships that go to Cambridge:
剑桥有四个奖学金
the John Elliot,the Fiske,um...one other...Pembroke;
John Elliot和Fiske 还有Pembroke
then there is the John Harvard fellowship.
还有一个是John Harvard奖学金
So I got the John Elliot,one of the 4.
我得到了John Elliot奖学金 四个之一
Immediately when I got it,I know that I got it obviously.
我得到后不久 我就得到消息了
It wasn't that I was ignoring it.
并不是我无视了它
But then I said why didn't I get the John Harvard fellowship.
但我想为什么没能得到John Harvard奖学金
Now there is no difference between them except for the names.
它们之间除名字不同外没任何区别
But that's immediately what my mind went to. And that,
但那是我的脑袋里立刻想到的
that was very important experience for me because I said
对我而言是很重要的经历 因为我说
"wow,look at you. "and that's when I started to recognize
“看看你” 我在那个时候开始意识到
the importance and the power of our evaluation.
我们的评估的重要性和威力
And how that can determine or even ruin
它是怎样决定或甚至毁掉
what should have been a celebration.
本该是一件值得庆祝的事
But once we recognize it,once we understand it,
但一旦我们认识它 一旦了解它后
we can dispute it. We can challenge it.
我们可以怀疑它 可以质疑它
We can reframe it and see the positive as well.
可以重组它 也能看到积极的一面
Again,all it's saying in cognitive therapy is let's be real.
此外 认知疗法就是要我们实际点
Making up or fabricating the 3rd M.
第三个M是虚构 或称捏造
This is when we create something ex nihilo,from nothing.
这是我们无中生有的时候
So for example,we personalize it or we blame.
比如 我们个人化或者归咎他人
We see this very often with people who are abused.
被虐待的人身上经常能看到这点
So an abused wife will very often say
受虐待的妻子经常会说
"It's my doing. It's my fault. I'm not behaving appropriately."
“是我做的 我的错 我做的不对”
Instead of rationally saying
而不是理智地说
"This guy is abusive. I'm out of here."
“这个家伙虐待我 我要离开”
That's irrational personalization.
那是不理性地个人化
It can also be the other way around.
它也会有别的方式
You know,I just did poorly on an exam
我有次考试成绩很差
and I blame my boyfriend or girlfriend for it.
我因此责怪我男朋友或女朋友
That's also unrealistic. I need to take responsibility.
那也是不现实的 我得承担责任
You got to remember Nathaniel Branden. No one is coming.
要记住Nathaniel Branden的例子 没有人会来
Take responsibility rather than blame.
承担起责任而不是责备别人
One of the key ideas (that)
Marva Collins和她的学生交流的
Marva Collins communicates to her students.
重要的观点之一
So again,it's not going to the personalizing...over-personalizing
不是过度个人化
or over-blaming,it's being real.
或过度责备 而是面对现实
And finally,emotional reasoning.
最后是情感的推理
I am envious; therefore I must be a bad person.
我满怀妒嫉 因此我肯定是个坏人
Or I'm experiencing danger
或我在试镜前
before a tryout therefore it must be dangerous.
遇到了危险 所以肯定很危险
Taking an emotion and making it into reality
选取一种情绪 让它成为现实
whereas instead of understanding an emotion is an emotion,
而不是把情感只当做情感
it doesn't necessary capture reality,
不必符合现实
it is my evaluation of reality.
而是我对现实的评估
Or,I'm extremely scared of failing...and therefore...
或者 我非常害怕失败 因此
it means that failing it's really dangerous,
意味着失败是很危险的
while in fact it's not. I'll get back up again very quickly,
实际不是的 我会马上回到这个话题
so it's having the correct evaluation,
所以要有正确的评估
correcting for the track,correcting for these errors.
更正轨迹 更正这些错误
Or feeling that,
更正"我很平庸
I'm second-rate and I'm no good in psychology or maths,
心理学或数学我学不好"之类的想法
and because I feel that,my evaluation of it is,well,
因为我有那种感觉 我的评估就是
I must really be second-rate and no good,
我肯定真的很平庸 学不好
instead having the rational belief of,well,let me try out,
而不是理性的想法 让我试一下
let me see how things go,correcting the distortions.
看看事情会怎么样 更正扭曲的想法
The key,once again,is to get real.
再说一次 关键是真实化
How do we get real through the questions that we ask?
我们如何通过我们的提问变真实?
I am going to give you just a few examples here;
我在这要给你们举几个例子
you are going to practice with those on your own.
你们要自己去练习
But here are just some of them.
这些是其中几个
First of all,is my conclusion tied to reality?
首先 我的结论和现实相关吗?
Second,is it rational? They are interconnected.
第二 那合理吗? 它们是相关联的
Am I ignoring something important?
我忽略了什么重要的事吗?
Like the fact that---you know the book did well afterwards---
比如 之后那本书销量很好
like the fact that there are other cool guys in 1504,and so on.
比如1504教室还有别的男孩 等等
What important evidence
什么重要的迹象
do I still need to take into consideration?
是我需要考虑的?
This is about disputing,it's evidence,it's get real.
进行辩论 举出证据 现实化
Look out,don't just zoom in on the geometric shapes,
但小心别只是进行几何形状的扩大
there are also children on the bus.
公交车上还有孩子
And this is what questions do. They open us up,
这是这些问题做的 让我们放开思绪
they open our vision and they create in your reality.
它们打开我们的视野 创造现实
What am I magnifying? What am I minimizing?
我夸大了什么?我在贬低什么?
Am I falling into the traps?
我陷入困境了吗?
Am I ignoring anything that is going well?
我忽略了什么进展很顺利的事吗?
Am I ignoring anything that is not going well?
我忽略什么进展不顺的事吗?
It's not about Pollyanna feel good at all costs,
这不是不计代价地盲目乐观
it's about being tied to reality. And finally,let me zoom out.
是要联系现实 最终缩小范围
What is the big picture.
大的画面是什么
To conclude,Ed Diener and Martin Seligman
结论是 Ed Diener和Martin Seligman
did very important research on extremely happy people.
对幸福无比的人们做了重要研究
This is tip of the stamp research.
这是对高端的研究
Looking at the 10 per cent of the happiest people out there,
看那些百分之十最幸福的人
people that we can learn from.
我们能从他们那里取经
And what they found was very interesting.
他们的研究结果很有趣
First of all,these people did not experience painful emotions
首先 这些人经历痛苦
any less times than the rest of the people,
不比其他人少
say the bottom 10 per cent or the mid 10 per cent.
比如最不幸福的10%或中间的10%
They experience painful emotions,
他们经历过痛苦
the difference between them and the rest was that they recovered
他们与剩下的人之间的区别是
more promptly as a result of different interpretations.
由于不同的诠释 他们恢复得更迅速
So when they felt down,they were optimistic instead of saying
所以他们沮丧时 他们很乐观 不说
"ok,so I'm going to feel down for the rest of the month",
“这个月剩下的日子我都会沮丧”
they said "ok,so I'm feeling down,big deal.
他们说“我很沮丧 没什么大不了”
What can I learn from it? What happen?
我能从中学到什么?发生了什么?
How can I make myself feel better?"
我怎样让自己感觉好点?
And then they recovered more promptly than the pessimists,
然后他们比悲观者恢复得更快
the people who remained depressed for a much longer time.
悲观者会沮丧很长一段时间
You see,events happen,things happen in the world,
事件发生 世上有很多事发生
very often out of our control.
经常不受我们的控制
We don't create everything that we encounter.
我们不能创造所有遇到的事物
And some of the events are bad,some are negative.
有些事件是不好的 有些是消极的
What matters more is what we do with them after,
更重要的是我们之后怎样对待它们
how we evaluate them. And what happens is that
怎样评估它们 事实上
our evaluation becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy,
我们的评估成了自我实现预言
because a pessimist will say "I'm in a bad mood now,
因为悲观者会说"我现在心情不好
it's going to last for a very long time,
会持续很长时间
it's not going to go away",whereas an optimist says
不会消失" 而乐观者会说
"it's temporary,it's going to go away"
"这是暂时的 会消失的"
and believes our self-fulfilling prophecies.
并相信我们的自我实现预言
If I believe that it will last for six months,
如果我认为它会持续六个月
it's much more likely,not necessarily,
它更有可能 不一定
but it's much more likely to last for six months
但更可能持续六个月
than if I say "that too shall pass".
比我说“那也会过去的”
And what we do with our beliefs
我们对待信仰的方式
is we create a downward spiral of depression,unhappiness,
是造一个向下的忧伤沮丧的螺旋
sadness or an upward spiral,capitalizing positive emotions
或一个向上的拥有积极情绪的螺旋
and having more and more of them,
并越来越多
what Barbara Fredrickson talks about
Barbara Fredrickson所说的
the "broaden and build" phenomenon. A lot of it is up to us.
“扩大和构造”现象大部分取决于我们自身
There are no short cuts. There are no easy steps to wellbeing,
没有捷径 通往幸福 成功
to success,to high level of beliefs in ourselves.
和自身更高水平的信念的道路并不容易
It takes work,it takes effort,whether it's work visualizing,
那需要付出和努力 无论是形象化
whether it's hard work and coping,
还是努力奋斗和积极面对
or whether it's work learning to dispute irrational thoughts.
或是学习如何消除非理性思想
And it's not enough to just understand it once
并不是弄明白一次
and then we are all set,
然后就一劳永逸
we are all inoculated for the rest of our lives.
我们一生都必须持续努力
If you want to continue working,
如果你想继续努力
we have to continue working at it.
我们必须一直致力其中
Let me move on...And talk about the question of "focus".
下个内容 讲"关注"的问题
Because just like if we focus on specific element
因为我们关注某一要素
of an event or not makes a difference,
或事件与否 有很大的区别
it applies on the macro level to our entire life.
它对我们整个生命的宏观层面有巨大影响
What I am going to do now is elaborate,
我现在要进行详细的阐述
go up higher level of the spiral of understanding and learning,
对一些我们经常讨论的
of something that we have talked about time and again.
关于某事的理解和学习螺旋进行更高层次分析
Ed Diener,who is also,I just mentioned his research,
Ed Diener 我刚提到他的研究
he is also the president,first president
他也是国际积极心理学协会的
of the International Positive Psychology Association,
第一任会长
he's from Illinois. After years of research,concludes,
他来自伊利诺州 经过多年研究 他发现
it appears that the way people perceive the world
对幸福而言 人们感知世界的方式
is much more important to happiness than objective circumstances.
比客观环境更重要
Now if you think about it,that makes a lot of sense.
如果你想一下的话 很有道理
We know a lot of people who seemingly have everything,
我们认识许多看起来拥有一切的人
whether it's wealth,whether it's wonderful friends and family,
无论是财富 或很好的朋友或家人
all their dreams have come true,and they are still miserable.
他们的梦想都已成真 但仍很痛苦
While there are people who have very little,
而有些人拥有的很少
who have experienced hardship after hardship
经历了一次次困境
and who never cease to celebrate life. Then there are people
而从没停止为生活感到欢庆 还有些人
who have everything going for them and really appreciate it,
他们拥有一切并很感激这一切
don't take it for granted and are happy. And there are people
不觉得理所当然 他们很快乐 有些人
who don't have much and never cease to complain.
拥有的不多 永远都在抱怨
In other words,it's not just the internal or...sorry,
换句话说 不只是内在的...抱歉
it's not just the external that matters,
重要的不只是外在
what matters more is the internal.
更重要的是内在
Happiness is not contingent on our status,
幸福不是取决于我们的处境
or the state of our bank account,
或我们银行账户里的金额
it's much more dependent on our state of mind,
更依赖于我们的思想状态
on what we choose to focus on.
依赖于我们选择关注什么
Because our emotions are determined
因为我们的感情
by external circumstances as well as internal,
由外部和内部状况一起决定
interpretation matters. For example,
如何去诠释很重要 比如
look at what Edison did,5,000 failures to the external observer,
看爱迪生如何对待5000次的失败
for him the evaluation was very different.
对他而言 评估和常人不同
The internal evaluation,the subjective evaluation,
内部评估 主观的评估
it was 5,000 times where I showed what doesn't work.
我证明了5000种方法不管用
And it's up to us to decide where we focus.
要关注什么由我们自己决定
Do we celebrate successes or take it for granted?
我们庆祝成功或视为理所当然?
Do we perceive failures and hardships as a disaster
我们觉得失败和困难都是灾难
or as an opportunity for growth? Emerson:
或是成长的机会? 爱默生说过
"to different minds the same world is a hell and a heaven."
“对不同思想而言 世界既是天堂又是地狱”
And Shakespeare:
莎士比亚说过
"Nothing is good or bad,but thinking makes it so."
“事情没有好坏之分 只是思想使然”
Now,I don't 100 per cent agree with Shakespeare,
我不是百分之一百同意莎士比亚
but he is to a great extent right. A person in ???
但从很大程度上看他是对的 住在达尔富尔的人
is living in hell,and it's very difficult to reframe,
就像生活在地狱中 很难改变环境
and to derive,and to look at the positive in that situation.
并在那样的处境中表现得积极乐观
Same for a person living in a concentration camp.
对住在集中营的人也一样
So there are external circumstances that matter.
所以有的外部情况会有影响
A person,a homeless person,you know,
一个人 无家可归的人
if you give them enough money for a home,for food,
如果给他们足够的钱买房子 买食物
for basic education,of course they will become happier
接受基础的教育 他们当然会更快乐
because of the change of external circumstances.
因为外部情况的改变
However,beyond the basic needs,beyond the basic freedoms,
然而 在基本需要和基本的自由外
it is mostly about how we perceive reality,
主要和我们如何认知现实有关
and we are able to make it into a heaven or a hell.
以及我们如何让生活变成天堂或地狱
Let's do an exercise
我们做个练习
that will capture this idea of "focus creating reality".
来帮助我们理解"专注创造现实"这一观点
So I have a question for you: how many geometric shapes?
我有个问题问你们 有多少几何图形?
Unfortunate,it's a great exercise but it only works once.
不幸 这个很棒的练习 只能做一次
Remember this,how you created your reality
记住这点 你如何创造现实
just based on the question that you asked.
基于你提的问题
We think when we look at the picture,
当我们看这幅图时我们在思考
you know not everyone of course is looking on the children
当然不是每个人都在看那个
on the bus on the clock,right?
时钟上的公共汽车上的那个小孩 对吗?
But before it was right in front of you and you didn't,
但它就在你面前 而你没看到
most of you,did not see it,because it is a question of focus.
你们许多人没有看到这点 是专注的问题
Very often we complain about life and we think,
我们经常抱怨生活 我们认为
you know,things are terrible and awful not realizing
事情很糟糕 很可怕 而没意识到
that we're the cause of it,either by imaging it
我们是它的起因 要么是在想象它时
and then beliefs become self-fulfilling prophesies,
然后我们的信念变成自我实现预言
or,because we just focus on what is not working.
或因为我们只专注于不对的方面
And one thing and this does not mean
而这并不意味着
that there are no objective terrible circumstances out there.
没有什么客观的糟糕的情况
But to a great extent,a great extent,we co-create our reality.
但很大程度上 我们一起创造了现实
You know one of the students
我的一个学生
who was in 1504 two years ago recommended this book to me---
两年前在1504教室 向我推荐这本书
Way of the Peaceful Warrior. And it's a wonderful book,
《深夜加油站遇见苏格拉底》是本好书
I just started reading it...and there is a movie on it,right...
我刚开始看 它有部同名电影 对的
I just started reading it yesterday,and I came across this...
我昨天才开始看 我看到这个...
you know coincidentally this parable,so I want to read it to you
这个寓言很巧合 我想读给你们听
The story that Dan Millman,the author,tells:
作者Dan Millman讲了一个故事
I met him on a construction site in the Middle West.
我和他在中东一个建筑工地认识
When the lunch whistle blew,
当午餐哨吹响时
all the workers would sit down together to eat.
所有的工人都会坐在一起吃饭
And everyday Sam would open his lunch pail and start to complain.
每天Sam都会打开午餐桶 开始抱怨
"Son of the gun,"he would cry,
"该死的家伙"他会大叫
"not peanut butter and jelly sandwich again!
"又是花生酱和果冻三明治
I hate peanut butter and jelly!"
我讨厌花生酱和果冻"
He whined about his peanut butter and jelly sandwiches
他埋怨着花生酱和果冻
day after day after day,
日复一日
until one of the guys in the work crew finally said:
直到一天工作组里的一个人终于说
"Sam,if you hate peanut butter and jelly so much,
"Sam 如果你这么讨厌花生酱和果冻
why don't you just tell your old lady
为什么不叫你老婆
to make you something different?"
给你做点别的?"
"What do you mean my old lady?" Sam replied,
"什么我老婆?"Sam回答说
"I'm not married,I make my own sandwiches."
"我没结婚 我自己做三明治"
You know,very often we make our own sandwiches
我们经常自己做三明治
and we don't even notice it. Because the questions that we ask,
而没意识到这点 因为我们问的问题
the questions that we ask determine our reality:
我们问的问题决定我们的现实
a peanut sandwich,or geometric shapes,or children on the bus,
花生三明治 几何形状 或车上的孩子
or salami,whatever it is. We very often create our own reality.
或香肠 无论什么 我们创造我们自己的现实
And if we understand this,we can transform,
如果我们理解这点 我们能改变
change the way that we perceive,change our focus,
改变我们认知的方式 改变关注的事
change our questions,
改变我们的问题
whether it's questions disputing irrational evaluations,
无论是辩论非理性评估
whether it's questions focusing on the positive,
或是关注积极面
and questions create a new reality.
还是创造新的现实的问题
There are essentially two archetypes
我们将在这里讨论
that I would like to discuss here,
本质上来说有两种原型
two archetypes that capture in many ways
在如何认知性地重建 加强 创造现实等
how we can cognitively reconstruct,enhance,create our reality.
多种途径有着两种原型
The two archetypes are the benefit-finder and the fault-finder.
两个原型分别是积极者和消极者
First of all,the fault-finder,the fault-finder is a person
首先消极者 消极者是
who always focuses on things that don't work,
总是专注不成功的事情的人
on the peanut butter and jelly,on things that are not going well
花生酱和果冻 专注进展不顺利的事
on problems in the relationship,on problem in him or herself,
专注交往中的问题 他或她自己的问题
problems with the job---the consummate complainer.
工作的问题 总是爱抱怨的人
Now,we all exist on the continuum of
我们都存在于消极和
between extreme fault-finding and extreme benefit-finding.
积极两个极端之间
You know there is no one
没有人
who is all the way on the extreme this way or that way,
总处于某一个极端
everyone is on somewhere on the continuum.
每个人都在这个集合当中的某处
What I'm going to argue for is to move a little bit more
我想要鼓励的是 从消极向积极的方向
from the fault-finding toward the benefit-finding,
逐渐移动
because there are many benefits to it that I'll discuss later.
因为这样有很多好处 我等下会讲到
The fault-finder,
消极者
I got the name from the work of Henry David Thoreau,
这名字出自梭罗的书中
the fault-finder will find faults even in paradise.
消极者甚至在天堂都能找到缺陷
The extreme fault-finder experiences resignation,
极端消极者总会经历辞职
learned helplessness. Why?
感到无助感 为什么?
Because he or she begins to really believe
因为他或她开始真的相信
that the terrible reality is very much out there independent of
糟糕的现实真的存在
what he or she thinks,
不受他或她的想法支配
not recognizing that they create that reality,
而没意识到是他们创造了那个现实
they begin to believe that no matter what they do,
他们开始相信无论他们做什么
no matter what job they find they have a terrible boss,
无论找什么工作 总有个糟糕的老板
no matter what partners they have
无论和什么人搭档
they are always awful and inconsiderate,
他们都很糟糕 不顾及别人
no matter what restaurant they go to the service is always awful,
无论去什么饭店 服务总是很糟糕
and they always keep on getting the same peanut butter
他们总是吃同样的花生酱
and jelly sandwich that they made for themselves.
和果冻三明治 是他们自己做的
And they resigned to the reality
他们向现实屈服
and that becomes a self-fulfilling prophesy of course,
那同时当然也让他们的存在
their existence.
变成自我实现预言
A fault-finder makes lemonade out of lemons,
消极者用柠檬榨柠檬汁
sorry,makes lemon out of lemonade.
抱歉 用柠檬汁做柠檬
The benefit-finder,research Julian Bauer,now at UCLA,
而积极者 加大洛杉矶分校的Julian Bauer做的研究
the benefit-finder is the opposite,focuses on what works.
积极者相反 专注于成功的事物
The benefit-finder looks on the bright side of life,
积极者专注生活的光明一面
finds the silver lining in the dark cloud,
在乌云笼罩中找到一丝白光
makes lemonade out of lemons,
用柠檬榨柠檬汁
不因讲师说太多陈词滥调而和他争吵 and doesn't fought an instructor for using too many clichés.
The benefit-finder finds the miracle in the common,
积极者能在普通中找到奇迹
Ralph Waldo Emerson,the consummate benefit-finder,
爱默生就是一个模范积极者
focusing on the positive and what works.
专注于积极面和进展顺利的事上
Now the problem here may be that
这里的问题也许是
the benefit-finder may be detached,
积极者也许会孤立地...
this is one of the criticisms of people who always see,
这是人们经常看到的一种批评
you know,the bright side of life,
只看到生活的光明面
and that is the problem if that is the case. Again,
这样的话的确是一个问题
this class is not advocating focusing only on the positive;
这节课不提倡只专注积极面
its focus is advocating reality.
它专注于提倡现实
And reality comprises both good and bad,
现实包含好的和坏的食物
reality comprises both geometric shapes
现实包含几何图形
and children on the bus,and the key is to focus on both.
和车上的孩子 关键在于要同时关注两者
So the detachment,
分离
the detached benefit-finder is certainly not an archetype
分离地看待事物的积极者 不是一个原型
that I would advocate nor would it lead to mental health
在长期条件下
in the long run.
它当然也不会使人心理健康
"There is a need in the world" ---of Nathaniel Branden---
Nathaniel Branden说过
"to respect reality."
“世界上需要尊重现实”
We don't create reality simply by the focus,
我们不能只凭专注创造现实
however,we are co-creator.
我们是共同创造者
Let me read you extensively from William James,
我给你们读一段William James的话
"Now however fixed these elements of reality may be,
"但这些实在的因素 虽然都非常固定
we still have a certain freedom in our dealings with them.
而我们对付它们 还是有一定自由的
Take our sensations,
拿感觉来说
THAT they are is undoubtedly beyond our control;
感觉的存在 我们虽不能控制
but WHICH we attend to,note,and
但是在我们的结论里 我们注意哪个
make emphatic in our conclusions depends on our own interests;
着重哪个 毕竟得凭我们个人的利益来决定
and,according as we lay the emphasis here or there,
着重之点不同
quite different formulations of truth result.
结果构成的真理可完全不同
We read the same facts differently.
事实全同 我们的看法可各异
'Waterloo',with the same fixed details,
同一个滑铁卢之战 具体情节绝无二致
spells a 'victory' for an Englishman;
而英国人看来是"胜利"
for a Frenchman it spells 'defeat'.
法国人看来是"失败"
So,for an optimist philosopher the universe spells victory,
同样 宇宙也如此 乐观主义者看作是胜利
for a pessimist,defeat. What we say about reality thus
悲观主义者看作是失败 我们对现实抱有怎样说法
depends on the perspective into which we throw it. "
全看我们怎么给他配景"
William James said these back in 1890,
这是William James在1890年说的
understanding how we co-create our reality.
理解我们如何共同创造现实
Here is one of my...one of my favorite poems by R.L. Sharpe:
这是我最喜欢的R.L. Sharpe的诗
Isn't it strange,how princes and kings,
"是不是很奇怪 王子和国王
and clowns that caper in sawdust rings,
在木屑圈e跳硖去的小丑
and common-people like you and me,
一如你我的凡人
are builders for eternity?
怎么会是永恒的打造者?
each is given a list of rules,
人人都拿到了一份规则表
a shapeless mass and a bag of tools;
一大块不成形的东西 一袋工具
and each must fashion your life is flown,
在生命流逝之前 人人都必须雕出
a stumbling block or a stepping stone.
一块绊脚石 或是一块垫脚石“
Very often what we get in the beginning
经常我们在开始得到的东西
is a large piece of stone. What do we do with it?
是一大块石头 我们怎么办?
Do we create it into a beautiful "David"?
我们把它凿成漂亮的"大卫"?
Chipping away the excess stone?
凿碎多余的石头?
Or,is it a barrier to our success?
或者它只是我们通往成功的障碍
And very often it is up to us,as we co-create our reality.
通常这是由我们决定的 因为我们共创现实
The stone is there,we are not responsible for it;
石头就在那 我们不用负责
but what we do with it,we are responsible for.
但我们用它做什么 我们要负责
Cognitive reconstruction
认知重建
is about learning to interpret things optimistically,
是要学习乐观地诠释事情
another words,in the positive light.
换句话说 要积极的肯定值得肯定之处
Ann Harbison,colleague of mine,
Ann Harbison 我同事
used to teach also with Philip Stone,
以前也和Philip Stone一起教书
said that "never let a good crisis go to waste".
说过“永远不要浪费一次好的危机”
Crises have the potential through growth.
危机在发展中有潜力
One of the books that we will talk about
我们将谈到的其中一本书
when we talk about relationships is Passionate Marriage
《热情婚姻》是关于婚姻关系的
by David Schnarch,who talks about crucibles in marriage.
作者David Schnarch 谈论婚姻中的考验
And what he says is that ...the thriving relationships,
他说 成功的婚姻
a relationships,not that have been,you know,
婚姻关系不是一直
all fine and dandy for years. These usually fail after a while.
和睦融洽的 往往会有争吵
But the relationships that go through crucibles,
而是经历过磨难
that have crises,disagreements and then,you know,
有过危机 有过分歧的婚姻关系
Thesis and Antithesis and then there is a Synthesis,
就像黑格尔的否定之否定规律
and there is a growth as a result of these hardships.
往往会因为经历过这些困难而获得更好的发展
And he says that there is no other way,
他说没有其他办法
again learn to fail or fail to learn,
学习失败或在失败中学习
there is no other way for a long-term success of a relationship.
维持长期的关系必须靠这个方法
Relationship does not,cannot look like this.
关系看起来不像这样
It has to have these ups and downs.
它必须有起有落
Never let a good crisis in a relationship go to waste.
从不错失关系中的一个好危机
That doesn't mean that every crisis needs to be resolved
不是说每个危机都要解决
and there are some that could end,and should end a relationship.
有些关系可以结束 也应该结束
But most crises can be solved and need to be dealt with.
但多数危机能被解决 需要处理好
Same on individual level,work by Warren Bennis,
在个人层面也是一样 Warren Bennis的研究表明
he is from USC,
他来自南加州大学
taught for a few years here at the Business School,
在这里的商学院执教过几年
has identified the leading leaders,
他鉴定了一群领袖人物
whether it's younger ones what he called,
无论是他称为“极客”的年轻一代
whom he called "the geeks",the thirty-year-olds,or elder ones,
或者是30多岁或更大的
"the geezers" he called them.
他称之为“怪杰”的老一辈
He has a book called Geeks & Geezers,
他出过一本叫《极客与怪杰》的书
where he talks about the differences
他在里面讨论了
between the two leadership styles,approaches,passions,
这两种领导风格 领导方式 激情以及
interests and there are numerous differences.
兴趣爱好的区别 有许多的不同之处
For example,you know,
比如
the geeks---the younger one talk about work-life balance,
极客 年轻一代会谈论工作生活平衡
the geezers don't know what he means by that.
怪杰们则不知道那是什么意思
You know it was usually,he,a man,
而男人工作
worked while the woman took care of the family and the man.
女人照顾家庭和男人
So that was for the geezers,for the older generation.
则是对怪杰而言的 对老的一代而言
The younger generation,they talk about work-life balance
年轻的一代 谈论工作生活平衡
and how they can incorporate all the elements of their lives.
他们如何结合生活中所有的元素
There are of course many more women in the geeks than the geezers
当然在极客中的女人数比怪杰中多
Numerous differences among the generation,one similarity.
两代人有无数不同点 但有一个相似点
All the great leaders,
所有的伟大的领袖
whether they were thirty-year-old or eighty-five years old,
无论是30岁或85岁
all of them had been through very rough crucibles
他们都经历过艰难的困境
and leave to tell the tale.
留下一段充满惊险的往事
Our most people go through crucibles,
我们大多数人经历过困境
but there are certain people
但有些人
who are able to find benefit in these crucibles
能从这些困境中找到益处
and grow as a results.
从而成长
Never let a good crisis go to waste,
永远不要错失一个好危机
whether it's professionally,whether it's interpersonally,
无论你在经历的是
whether it's intra-personally in terms of
职业上或人际关系上
what you are experiencing.
或是内在个性上的危机
But four years ago or five years ago,
四年或五年前
when I was still a resident tutor in Leverett house,
我还是Leverett宿舍的住宿导师
and we had one of these pre-business events
我们举办了开学前活动
where we talked about the upcoming year
我们讨论了即将来临的一年的情况
and the recruiting and so on.
和招聘事宜等等
That particular year was a terrible year,
那一年是很糟糕的一年
Goldman Sachs was laying off,wasn't recruiting on campus,
高盛在裁员 没有校园招聘
Credit Suisse,First Boston they were laying off as well,
瑞士信贷 第一波士顿银行也在裁员
Deutsche Bank,first time in his history was laying off employees
德意志银行建行以来第一次裁员
really bad market. And we talked about this,each of us gave it,
市场环境非常糟糕 我们讨论时每个人
what should be about the market and what they can do,
都在估测市场的形势和他们能做什么
very sober presentation. And then one of the students,
非常严肃的话题 然后一个学生
you know my students Sean Fieldscoy,was a senior then,
我的学生Sean Fieldscoy当时大四
was sitting there,Had studied positive psychology there.
他坐在那里 他学了积极心理学
He put up his hand and said:
他举起手说
"Tal,you know,as...you know you portrait a very pessimistic
"Tal 你描绘了一个非常悲观的
and negative picture,
消极的画面
but as a teacher of Positive Psychology
但作为一个积极心理学老师
can you maybe shed some optimism here?" And you know,
你能否说点积极的?"
few chuckles in the audience and then silence.
观众中有些窃笑 然后是一片寂静
And everyone is looking at me,
每个人都看着我
I don't know what to say and my immediate reaction was to say
我不知道说什么 我第一反应是说
"Well Sean things happen for the best." Exactly. (laughs)
“Sean 事出皆有因” 没错
And then,
然后
just before it came out of my mouth I said...I thought to myself,
当我说出口前 我心想
"Actually I don't believe that."
"其实我不相信"
I don't believe that things happen for the best.
我不相信事出皆有因
But while I don't believe that things happen for the best,
但虽然我不相信事出皆有因
I do believe that some people are able to make the best
我的确相信有些人能够因事制宜
of things that happen,and there is a very big difference here.
这里有一个很大的区别
Because when I say "I'm not happy about what just happen here,
因为当我说“我不满意刚发生的事”
I don't like it,I much rather have the market be a good market,
我不喜欢它 我更希望市场是好市场
where people are hiring,
人们就业很容易
where they all come to me on a silver platter and offer me a job.
许多人争相向我提供工作
Of course,I would much rather have that.
当然 我更情愿那样
So things don't happen for the best necessarily,
所以事出未必有因
but there are some people who accept the situation
但有些人接受这种情况
and then are able to make the best of it.
并且能够因事制宜
The same with any crisis. Do you think the leaders,
对任何危机而言都一样 你们以为领袖们
whether they are the eighty- or ninety-year-olds,
无论他们80或90岁
invited those crucibles into their lives
会主动在生活中寻求严酷的考验吗
want these crucibles to happen?
会想让这些困难发生吗?
Do you think partners go into a relationship and say
你觉得处在关系中的伙伴会说
"let's look for that crucible,
"我们寻找考验
let's really fight so that we can have a healthy relationship"?
我们吵一架让我们的关系更健康吧"?
Of course not! But when it happens,
当然不会 但如果真的发生这种情况
that's when they make the best of it.
他们会充分利用它
You know,stuff happens,
有些事会发生
and we can either let it pollute or make fertilizer out of it.
我们要么无动于衷要么从中获取利益
I want to show you an example once again of a leader,
我再举一个领袖的例子
who is a consummate benefit-finder.
他是一个模范积极者
[MUSIC]
Wow. We are honored to be talking with Neilson Mandela,
我们很荣幸能和曼德拉聊天
the former president of South Africa,whose unshakable courage,
南非前任总统 他不可动摇的勇气
his faith and integrity have inspired millions to see
他的信仰和正直鼓舞了数千万人
what is possible in their own lives.
看到自己生命中的可能
I've had the pleasure,the honor of meeting Mr. Mandela
我很高兴 很荣幸在此之前几次见过
on a couple of occasions before and I will tell you,
曼德拉先生 我告诉你们
to be in his presence is really,to be in your presence
和他在一起真的 和你在一起
is like being a presence of royalty and grace at the same time.
就像同时和庄严和优雅在一起
I would think,I wonder how does a man spend 27 years in prison,
我想知道一个人在狱中度过27年
put there by an oppressor,
被压迫者迫害入狱
and come out of that experience with not a heart of stone,
出来后没有铁石心肠
not a cold heart
没有漠不关心
but a heart that is willing to forgive and embrace.
而怀着愿意原谅和容纳的心
I remember talking to you one night of our dinner,
我记得一晚吃晚饭时和你聊天
and you had said to me that our hatred for the oppressor
你对我说 我们对压制者的憎恨
was so intense we did not see the value of talking to him.
太过强烈 我们没有看到和他谈话的价值
So at what point did you see the value of letting go of that hatred
那么你看到了什么价值 要放下仇恨
and begin the process of talking?
并开展对话?
Well,let me say first,that is a great tragedy
首先我想说 这是一个很好的策略
to spend the best of your lives in prison.
把一生最好的时间花监狱中
But although it looks ironical,there are advantages in that.
虽然看起来很讽刺 但有好处
If I had not been at the prison,I have not...
如果我没有入狱 不会有...
I would not be able to achieve the most difficult,
我不会完成毕生中
a task in life,and that is changing yourself.
最困难的任务 那改变了你自己
I would not have an opportunity.
我不会有那样的机会
I had that opportunity because in prison you have
我有那个机会是因为 在监狱里你有
what we don't have in our work outside prison,
在监狱外工作所没有的
the opportunity to sit down and think,which is an important part
机会 可以坐下思考 这是重要部分
Did you need 27 years of it though?
但你需要27年吗?
You could have taken a few days,a week,a vacation.
你可以用几天 几周 一个假期
Did you need 27 years?
你需要27年吗?
Now,
好
did it happen for the best that he spent 27 years of his life?
他花了27年是有意义的吗?
Certainly when he experienced it,it was painful,it was awful,
当然他经历时 很痛苦 很可怕
but he was able to transform this.
但他能改变这个
And to,even in that situation,to see the positive.
甚至在那个情况下 看到积极方面
And when we transform that,
当我们改变那个
those who know the history of what happen to him,
那些知道他经历过什么事的人
when he started to look at the positive,
当他开始看这积极方面
even there are the opportunities in prison
即使在监狱也有机会
when he changes his mind set. In other words,
当他改变思维模式 换句话说
not the external circumstances,
不是外部情况
the external circumstances actually begin to change.
外部情况确实开始改变
Another benefit-finder,
另一个积极者
"a pessimist sees difficulty in every opportunity,
"悲观者在每个机会中看到困难
an optimist sees the opportunity in every difficulty."
乐观者在每个困难中看到机会"
And you don't want to argue with him.
你不会想跟他争论
I want to end by telling you a story,
我想在结尾给你讲一个故事
a personal story about my experiences throughout the years.
一个关于我几年间经历的个人故事
Some biographical detail,
一些自传细节
something that most of you did not know.
一些你们多数人不知道的事
And I am going to tell it to you first
我要告诉你们
from the perspective of the fault-finder.
先从消极者的角度
I have a mild case of ADD,
我有轻微的注意力缺陷障碍
it makes things very difficult for me,
这让事情变得非常困难
it's difficult for me to focus,my mind wanders often,
我很难集中精神 我的脑子经常游离
and I really struggle with it constantly.
我真的不断地与它斗争
When I was in high school,
当我读高中时
I really wanted to get into a lucrative program in mathematics,
我很想进入一个数学的赚钱项目中
did not pass the entry exam,I was very disappointed,
没通过入选考试 我很失望
I did not make it. Becoming a professional squash player
我没做到 成了专业壁球运动员
was a dream for me since the age of 11.
是我11岁以来的梦想
That is the thing that I thought about constantly,
那是我一直会想的事情
that was the most important thing for me at the time.
那时这是我最重要的事
I wanna to be a professional player.
我想当一个专业选手
At the age of twenty,
20岁时
I was about to complete my military service in Israel
我在以色列马上就要服满兵役
and I got injured on the squash court
我在壁球场受了伤
and pulled the muscle in my back.
拉坏了背部的肌肉
The doctor gave me an option of being operated on,
医生让我选择 或者动手术
which was a big risk,or giving up my professional career.
这有很大风险 或者放弃职业生涯
I chose to give up my professional career,
我选择放弃我的职业生涯
a dream that I had from a very young age. It was a real blow.
一个我儿时的梦想 这个打击很大
I went to Cambridge,
我去了剑桥
after graduating from Harvard and I enrolled in a PhD program.
哈佛毕业后 我参加一个博士项目
I was the only student in my PhD program to fail,
我是那个项目中唯一没通过的
I was thrown out of the program. It was humiliating;
我被赶出了这个项目 很没面子
it seemed like a waste of a year
像浪费了一年
because I did not even get a master's degree.
因为我甚至没拿到硕士学位
It was a real tough experience.
这真的是个很艰难的经历
At Harvard,as a graduate student,I took,
在哈佛 作为研究生
with all the other students,my qualifying general exams.
我和其他学生一起 参加资格统考
Out of all the graduate students who took that exam,
在所有参加那个考试的研究生中
I was the only one who failed it.
我是唯一没有通过的
Once again,a really humiliating experience,
又是一个非常丢脸的经历
walking around William James and everyone knows their results,
走在William James楼边 大家都知道成绩
it was tough. Not only that,I was given provisional,
这很难堪 不只那样 我被临时
the provisional option of staying in the program.
临时选择留在这个项目中
They said to me,not only do you need to pass next year's exam
他们对我说 你不仅要通过明年考试
when you take it with the next class,
要和下一届一起考
you have to pass it with flying colors or you are out.
你还要出色地通过考试 否则就出局
So,while the rest of the semester,
剩下的这个学期
while working on the dissertations,writing,
忙着于论文和写作的同时
almost graduating I had to go back to the basics
我几乎快毕业还得回去看最基本的知识
and go over the whole material again.
把所有教材再复习一遍
God,I am so unlucky.
天啊 我太不幸了
I want to share with you some biographical facts about my life,
我想说一些我生活中的某些自传性事实
you know,I have a mild case of ADD,
我有轻微注意力缺陷障碍
which is great,you know why?
这很棒 知道为什么吗?
Because,it actually forces me to only study things
因为 这实际迫使我只能学
that I love,things that I care about,
我喜欢的东西 我关心的东西
because anything else,my concentration just goes away.
因为其他的事情 我就集中不了精神
So it's like,I have an internal mechanism
所以就像我有一个内部机制
that forces me to focus on the ultimate currency,
强迫我专注最终的东西
on things that make me happy. And
专注让我快乐的东西
I only study things that I'm passionate about,it is wonderful.
我只学我热爱的东西 这很棒
You know,when I was in high school,
我读高中时
I really wanted to get into a certain program,
非常想进某个项目
in a very lucrative program,and I didn't get in,
一个可以赚钱的项目 但没能进去
I failed the entrance exam,
我入选考试没通过
which turned out to be a blessing in disguise,
这最终是塞翁失马
because it gave me so much more time to practice and play squash,
因为它让我有更多时间练习打壁球
and I ended up winning international championships
我最终赢得了国际冠军
in the following year,
在第二年
which I wouldn't have done had I been in that program.
如果我进了那个项目就不会做到了
When I was in the University of Cambridge,
当我在剑桥大学时
I was in a PhD program,and I was the only one in my class,
我在一个博士项目 我是班里唯一
and as far as I know,
据我所知
the only one in years to be thrown out of the program.
数年来唯一被赶出这个项目的人
And it was actually a very important experience,you know,
这其实是个很重要的经历
I got out of Harvard,I was arrogant,
我哈佛毕业时 很自负
I thought I was holier than thou,
我认为自己比谁都神圣
and this was a real humbling experience
这是个非常令人羞辱的经历
that was especially important for me,
对我而言尤其重要
because the next year I went to work in Asia,
因为第二年我去亚洲工作
and there,the worst that I could do was to be arrogant.
在那里 自负是最糟糕的事情
So this humbling experience actually helped me
所以这个令人羞辱的经历
a great deal in my future career,
对我后来的生活有很大帮助
as well as helped me put things in perspective.
也帮助我正确对待事情
When I came to Harvard,I was the only one in my program
当我来到哈佛 我是项目中唯一
to fail the general qualifying exams,
没通过资格统考的人
it was a hard blow,it was difficult,
这是沉重的打击 很艰难
but it turned out to be a very good experience,you know why?
但结果是个很好的经历 知道为什么?
Because I had to study the exact same material
因为我得把相同的教材
and these huge books and articles all over again,
这些厚厚的书和文章重新学习一遍
and know them not just at the basic level,
不只是达到基本水平
I had to know them extremely well because that was the condition
我要学得非常好 因为这是条件
that the professors gave for me staying in the program.
是教授让我留在这个项目组的条件
And it was so good because I learned the material so well
这非常好 因为我把教材融会贯通
that I know social psychology today probably
我的社会心理学 现在大概
better than anyone I know,and that helps me a great deal.
比我认识的任何人都好 这帮了我很大忙
It helps me a great deal in putting together this course 1504,
它帮我把这个1504课程整合起来
and there is no place I would rather be than here.
没什么地方比这里更让我喜欢待的
God,I am so lucky.
天 我真幸运
Thank you. Same reality,different interpretations.
谢谢 同样的事实 不同的诠释
Just remember,much of what we experience,
只要记住 我们经历的大部分事情
we co-create. See you next week.
我们参与创造 下星期见